♪ Oh, Mr. Tailor ♪
["Mr. Tailor" playing]
♪ Holding the scissors ♪
♪ One cut, and it's settled ♪
[gunshots]
[T-Bak] Why are there guns?
- [gunshots in the distance]
- I can't handle that!
I'll charge in!
[Karla] I don't want anything
to happen to Brother Atoy.
[Paldo] Go inside.
Check how many enemies there are.
- [grunts and groans]
- [gunshots]
[grunts]
[Uno] You okay, Emerson?
- [Emerson] I'm fine.
- [grunts and groans]
[Cita] What? They went there?
Are they so angry at the world
that they'd risk their lives?
[Denden] Maybe they
just really wanted to help.
[Cita] My God. I hope they'll be safe.
Atoy! [echoing]
[gunshot]
- [music swells]
- [gunshot]
[clangs]
PREVIOUSLY
[Emerson] Atoy! [echoing]
[gunshots]
[Karla] Hey, foreigner! Look here!
Put Brother Atoy down!
[Samir speaks in Russian] Shut your mouth!
[Karla] Put him down!
[metal clangs]
[gunshots]
[Uno] Good to see you alive, sir.
Thank you. Where's Lily?
- [Lily] Where's Samir?
- He escaped.
[Atoy] You should call
Colonel Mercado immediately.
Are you impressed now?
See? We toppled the enemies.
I don't want anything to happen to you--
Of course, I love you.
[teasing]
[T-Bak] You really love us, Brother Atoy!
[Olga] Hold on.
You might not be able to take this.
- [Atoy] Why? Did something happen?
- [Olga] You are Ibyang's real father.
She's your child, Atoy.
[dramatic sting]
[Ibyang] Tatoy?
[Ibyang] You're my family?
[Atoy] Yes, Ibyang.
[Ibyang sobs] You're… You're my father?
[Atoy] I am.
[music swells]
[suave theme music playing]
[motorcycle revving]
[sewing machine whirring]
[scratches]
[snipping]
[sewing machine clacking]
- [gun cocks]
- [gunshots]
[thumps and gunshots]
- [music intensifies]
- [clicking]
[snipping]
- [music swells]
- [electronic blipping]
[music fades]
It's official now?
[softly] Yes.
You're really my Tatoy?
[Atoy chuckles softly]
It's very official.
[sobs]
But… Why?
I spent a long time wondering
where my parents were.
But they were right beside me all along.
[sobbing]
Why didn't we know sooner?
Well, Ibyang,
maybe that's just how life is.
[sentimental music playing]
Sometimes there are things
we just can't explain.
Like threads,
tangled together.
But eventually, they straighten out.
All of that…
is because of Him.
But if Mama Olga isn't my mother…
then who is?
[music fades]
[melodramatic music playing]
I know the truth now, Audrey.
Janine is not really our child.
She is our daughter.
[gasps]
- [sobbing]
- [soft drama music playing]
[broken voice, in English]
It was you all along.
You are my baby girl.
[Audrey, in English] My baby girl.
[sobs, in English] My baby.
[sobbing]
[Audrey sobbing, in English] I'm so sorry.
Aunt Audrey…
My mama.
My baby.
[sobs] My baby.
[sobs]
[dramatic music playing]
[sobbing]
Atoy, thank you for coming back.
I'm so happy because
you returned to your family.
Thank you, Father.
I prayed for nothing else but…
to have my family whole and…
for all of you to be safe.
It was granted to you
because you are a good son…
and a good man, Atoy.
[somber music playing]
Long live Atoy! The son of the thread!
Long live!
[all] Long live! Long live!
- [cheering]
- [hopeful music playing]
[Emerson] Long live Atoy!
The Master Cutter of Tabang Lupa!
[cheering, clapping]
- [Paldo] Our idol in everything!
- [soft sobbing]
[cheering, clapping]
One big community hug!
[cheering]
[Audrey chuckles]
[Audrey sobbing]
- [all] Atoy! Atoy!
- Wait.
[all] Atoy! Atoy! Atoy! Atoy!
- Atoy! Atoy! Atoy!
- Ibyang! Ibyang!
- Janine.
- [all] Atoy! Atoy!
- Ibyang.
- Janine.
[all] Atoy!
[music fades]
[melancholic music playing]
[smooches]
[speaking softly] Stay here for now.
[indistinct]
[music fades]
Janine, child.
[sobs] I'm sorry.
Sorry for… everything I've done.
[in English] No, no.
You don't need to apologize.
[Janine] No.
I should ask forgiveness because…
I was stubborn.
Well,
the only reason I did that
is because even if I get scolded,
it'll be my mommy and daddy
who will get mad at me, anyway.
I was also demanding,
especially with Daddy.
Because this was the first time
I felt what it was like to have a family.
And it turns out
you're not really my parents.
[gentle music playing]
We understand that, Janine.
And despite everything that happened…
you've become dear to us too, Janine.
I felt that.
So, thank you still,
because even for a short while,
I felt what it was like to have
a family and be part of one.
[sobs]
Can I
not go back to Mama Roma?
Can you just take me to the orphanage?
Why?
Who said you were going back there?
[Atoy] You have a home.
We will adopt you, Janine. [sniffles]
[sobbing]
Child…
We love you very much.
[sobbing]
But Ibyang…
I even told her to leave.
She'll just be angry with me.
Ibyang?
She's tough, but she's kind.
Do you know, when she learned the truth,
she was sad and worried for you, child.
She even looked for you.
So, I'm sure
she'll understand our decision.
[in English] Okay?
[in English] Thank you. Thank you.
Come, my child. Let's go.
[sobbing]
[music fades]
[reporter, in English]
It has been identified
that the exchange of gunfire
that happened earlier today
was caused by the secret army connected
to the current ambassador of Zahran,
Viktor Petrov.
[in English] As of the moment,
they are trying to reach Mr. Petrov,
but he is nowhere to be found.
[suspicious music playing]
Hon, look. Isn't that Atoy? There, see.
[in English] Yes. It's him.
So, what now?
That means he might already
be with Audrey.
[in English] Good.
[Martina, in English] Good?
This is a problem.
[in English] It's not.
Because if we see Atoy,
then most likely he and Audrey
are together in one place.
It will be easier to erase them
from the world.
[Red] So, if I were them,
I'd enjoy it while it lasts.
[music fades]
I'll take them all down at once.
[tense music playing]
I slammed him against the wall.
- Oh?
- Oh, yes.
Then I twisted his arm.
- And I brushed his chest with punches!
- That's amazing!
He died. It swelled.
- [group] Ah.
- Dead, yes!
- Wasn't that--
- Dead, as in dead.
Uno did that, right?
- Yes.
- Oh!
[Emerson] No, just a little--
I knew it. Your stories sound exaggerated.
- No, he did little…
- Well, me,
- …Uno did little--
- I believe Emerson!
- You're my number one hero!
- [teasing]
Wow, wow! So sweet!
Like what I'm drinking! Hmm!
- I'll sip your eyes!
- [laughing]
But we really need to celebrate!
Not just Atoy's safety,
but Tabang Lupa's safety!
Exactly! That's right!
That's how it should be!
I'm game! I'll help you.
- [Siony] Okay. Oh!
- Okay, huh. So--
- Yes.
- So how do we celebrate?
- Uh, I know!
- [Nestor] What?
[in English] Boodle fight!
[exclaiming]
[all, in English] Boodle fight!
Boodle fight!
- [in English] Yes!
- [all, in English] Boodle fight!
Thank you, Lord, for not abandoning us
and for keeping us away from harm.
All of us.
[gentle music playing]
Lord, and to you also, San Antonio.
Thank you for not abandoning us.
Thank you for everything. First,
for friends, true friends
who were really there for us.
Second, for giving me
courage and strength.
And third,
for giving us a child.
[gentle music playing]
[soft chuckle]
Even before we asked,
she was already here.
She had been with us all along.
Thank you, Lord.
In the name of the Father, the Son,
and the Holy Spirit…
Child, from now on, I promise you,
I will do everything for you.
Hmm. Because I'm your child,
your love for me is times ten million?
Oh, not just ten million.
Ten billion or even a trillion!
Oh, wow.
So, I can still be pesky?
[light music playing]
Hmm. Pesky? That's what you must never do.
Because if you are, I'll still scold you.
Hmph.
You're not Master Grumpy anymore,
now you're Daddy Grumpy.
- [Audrey chuckles softly]
- Just joking!
I still can't believe it.
I've been with my parents all along.
I just didn't know.
Us too, my child.
I'm just happy
that even though our paths strayed,
we still found each other…
and we didn't lose you, child.
[chuckles softly]
Hmm. [smooches]
[Audrey] Hmm… [sighs]
- Tatoy.
- Oh?
Where is Mama Olga?
[light music playing]
Here it is. I'll do it.
I'll do it, I'll do it. That's it.
- Let's go.
- [Karla] Let's go.
[in English] Karla! Do you need help?
Karla, I'll do the talking.
I'll handle it.
No, bro. We're fine.
Just a moment.
- Is that okay?
- [Karla] Yes.
Okay. [sighs]
So, since your mission here is done,
are you leaving?
[sneaky music playing]
I don't know yet.
But maybe.
Yes. Just for a short while.
Just a short while.
Do you like Karla?
Why, bro?
You, do you like Karla?
Yes.
Then why did you choose someone else?
[chuckles]
You know, the people here told me…
you never courted Karla before.
You let your chances pass.
And now, when you learned someone
else might court her,
suddenly you make a move. What's that?
What's that, bro?
You know,
that's not a good move.
Because you like her,
but you're too late, bro.
- [chuckles softly]
- [sighs]
There's nothing wrong with that.
People's feelings can change.
[in English] Gavin. Babe!
[in English] Where have you been?
I've been looking for you.
[chuckles softly] You're making a move,
but you already have a girlfriend.
[chuckles softly] Let's go.
[Uno] Maybe they're looking for him there.
- [Denden mutters]
- Excuse me!
[Karla, indistinct]
- [in English] Babe.
- [sniffles]
[in English] Hello? [chuckles softly]
What happened to you?
I've been trying to call you,
but you didn't answer.
- Are you ghosting me?
- I have personal problems.
[in English] Aww. That's too bad.
[in English] Um, anyway…
I was invited by couple influencers.
They want to collab,
and since it's for couples,
I need you to join me! It's for charity.
[in English] For charity or for yourself?
[in English] What?
You just want to do this
for your followers.
To pretend in front of them.
But in truth, you don't want to do this.
Just now, I told you
I have personal problems.
[in English] But you didn't bother
to ask me about it.
Don't you care about me?
The people here in Tabang Lupa
are more genuine.
More genuine?
Who's more genuine?
Your friend? Karla?
[in English] Yes.
[pensive music playing]
Ibyang,
the reason I wanted to help
save your Daddy Atoy is because…
I want you to be happy.
[gentle music playing]
I'm sorry for…
lying to you.
Sorry also for being strict with you.
Forgive me.
It's okay.
I'm not angry.
My love for you won't change, Mama Olga.
Really?
Yes. I'm thankful.
[Ibyang] Because I met you.
Because even if you're my fake mama,
you're the reason
I'm now with my real parents.
Thank you so much, Mama Olga.
You know, you'll be
a best actress someday.
- You cry so well!
- Hey!
This isn't TV-series acting.
These are real tears.
But seriously, Ibyang.
I'll really miss you.
You know, if Atoy weren't your father,
and you hadn't found your real parents,
I would adopt you.
Thank you very much.
I'll miss you too, Mama Olga.
- [soft drama music playing]
- [sobs]
[Atoy] Olga, thank you.
You completed my family.
If you miss Ibyang, just call.
Is video call okay?
Because when I get to the States,
I might be busy.
I'm claiming it…
I'll be famous
when my Hollywood film comes out.
Ah, Hollywood?
Wow! Really?
- Yes!
- That's amazing.
Right?
[chuckles softly]
Okay then. [sniffles]
Uh…
[music fades]
[melodramatic music playing]
[smooches]
[sobs] Goodbye.
- [Atoy] Take care.
- Take care.
- [Olga] I'll go ahead.
- [softly] Okay.
[Cita] Sorry, I just accompanied
Janine upstairs.
I'll go ahead.
Uh, Godmother.
I'm sorry if I kept you out of my life.
Because, well, that's how it is.
Even after all these years…
it still hurts.
I understand you, Atoy.
I was the one at fault.
I made the mistake.
I get why you're angry.
That's just it.
[sighs] I couldn't bring myself
to be angry at you, because…
of course, I already consider you
as my mother.
[sighs] So even if it hurts…
the good things you did for me
outweigh it.
[soft drama music playing]
Atoy…
Godmother.
Let's just forget everything
that happened.
No… No.
No, Atoy.
[sobs]
- No.
- Godmother, let's just forget it.
I need to tell you this. [sobs]
I need to face it
and accept all my mistakes.
[sobs]
I confessed to Julie.
My conscience was eating me alive.
[sobbing] And I'm thankful she forgave me.
She even entrusted you
and your father to me, Atoy.
[sobs]
I don't expect you to forgive me
the way your mother did,
but…
but--
- [sobs]
- Godmother…
[sobbing]
It's okay.
We're family.
- I forgive you.
- [sobbing]
[music fades]
I don't want to lose a mother again.
Mmm.
[sobbing]
I'm right here, son.
My child?
[both chuckle]
- [sobbing]
- [softly] Thank you.
[Cita] Thank you.
[sobbing]
[melodramatic music playing]
[sobs]
Godmother, you know…
[chuckles softly]
It's crazy.
Being locked up that long
makes you so hungry.
[chuckles]
So, can I ask a favor?
Can you cook my favorite tinola,
Godmother?
Tinola with lots of green papaya
and chili leaves?
- That's it!
- Of course!
You'll be spoiled!
But I'll cook it tomorrow, okay?
Tomorrow? Why tomorrow, Godmother?
- Because they prepared a feast--
- I'm so hungry--
Because Father Peping and Kapitana
prepared a feast for you,
to celebrate your return.
Oh? Why? I'm not an overseas worker.
[chuckles]
Everyone's just happy
because you're home, Atoy.
[music fades]
[phone ringing]
[tense music playing]
[in English] Hello, sir?
[music swells]
[electronic blipping]
[intense music playing]
- [groans]
- You're the bald devil!
- [Nestor] Hey!
- Get your filthy hands off Ibyang!
- No! Let me go!
- [Kurt grunts]
- Brother Kurt!
- Let's go!
[in English] Hello, Red!
Ah, you monster! You demon!
Where are the children?
Give me back the children!
I'll make these kids suffer.
I'll profit from them.
That's one of the major concentration
camps of the terrorist group Obsidian.
That's the international
human trafficking syndicate.
If that's where they were taken,
what do we do?
How do we get them back?
No matter what happens,
I'll get our child.
UP NEXT
If this has to be my last mission,
I'll do it.
♪ Holding the scissors ♪
♪ One cut, and it's done ♪
♪ Fix it ♪
Subtitle translation by: Rachel C. Arias